Inventory of the Eastern European Oral History Project Interviews
Hoover Institution Archives
Eastern European Oral History Project interviews
1999-2001
2000C8
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Sound recordings of interviews of Polish, Romanian, and other Eastern European political leaders, writers and others, and Western experts on Eastern Europe, relating to political conditions in Poland, Romania and elsewhere in Eastern Europe. Includes selected transcripts of interviews and related written matter. Project sponsored by the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace. Interviews conducted by Laura Cosovanu, staff member of the Hoover Institution and others.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2000 and 2001.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Sound recordings of interviews of Polish, Romanian, and other Eastern European political leaders, writers and others, and Western experts on Eastern Europe, relating to political conditions in Poland, Romania and elsewhere in Eastern Europe. Includes selected transcripts of interviews and related written matter. Project sponsored by the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace. Interviews conducted by Laura Cosovanu, staff member of the Hoover Institution and others.
Cosovanu, Laura.; Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace.; Europe, Eastern--Politics and government.; Phonotapes.; Poland--Politics and government.; Romania--Politics and government.
- Selected partial transcripts of interviews, clippings on interviewees, and related notes (Folder 1: 1)
- Sound recordings on sound compact cassettes, 1999-2001; 24 sound cassettes
  - Ana Blandiana and Romulus Rusan interview (Box 1)
    Access
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0006693
  - Anatoli Gremalschi interview (Box 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0010584
  - Andrei Plesu interview (Box 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0010586
  - Cristian Ionescu interview, 16 May 2000 (Box 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0010590
    Scope and Contents note
    Director General, Department for Parliamentary Information
  - Herbert Kaiser interview, 31 March 2000 (Box 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0010583
    Deputy Chief of Mission, Bucharest, early 80s.
  - Hoover Institution luncheon honoring Michael I, King of Romania, 19 October 2000 (Box 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0006447
    Speakers:
    George Shultz, Elena Danielson, Michael I.
    Includes the soundtrack of a film depicting the return of Michael I to Romania.
  - Ion Iliescu interview (Box 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0010591
    Former Romanian president
  - Ion Ratiu interview (Box 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0006696
  - Lucia Hossu Longin interview, 19 May 2000 (Box 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0010589
  - Michael I, King of Romania, interview at the Hoover Institution, 20 October 2000 (Box 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0006448
  - Miroslav Kusy interview (Box 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0010592
    Former chief of staff for the office of the president of Czechoslovakia, Vaclav Havel. A political philosopher from Slovakia, a prominent personality of the 1968 Prague Spring. He was expelled from public and academic life, persecuted and imprisoned. As one of the original signatories of Charter 77, he became an active participant in the dissident movement, which culminated in the Velvet Revolution of 1989. The arrest and trial of Kusy and Carnogursky in the summer and autumn of 1989 was one of the last major events in the old regime. Since '89, he has been elected to the Federal Parliament, and served as Rector of Comenius University in Bratislava. Board member of the Czech Helsinki Committee for Human Rights; heads the UNESCO Chair on Culture of Peace, Democracy, and Human Rights.
  - Nicolae Ionescu interview (Box 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0010594
    Deputy General Manager, Romanian official bulletin monitor official
  - Nicolae Ratiu interview (Box 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0010585
  - Petre Andrei interview (Box 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0010588
    former politician before the communist takeover, former political prisoner in the communist prisons
  - Professor Janos Kis interview (Box 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0006449
  - Radu Filipescu interview (Box 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0010582
    Leader of the Group for Social Dialogue, former political dissident
  - Roman Petre interview, 30 April 2000 (Box 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0010596
  - Silviu Brucan interview (Box 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0006694
  - Thomas W. Simons interview (Box 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0010587
  - Ticu Dumitrescu interview, 15 March 2001 (Box 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0010597
    President, Association of Former Political Prisoners, Romania (1990-); president, International Union of Former Political Prisoners from Eastern Europe (1991-1998).
  - Zofia Fedorowicz-Grzelak interview, 27 January 2000-28 January 2000 (Box 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2000c8_a_0010593
    Interview concerns the conception of federal solution for Central Europe supported by Polish Labor Party during World War II and in exile. It contains the reminiscence of Wacaw Iwanowski.